<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism | </title>
    <link>/tags/autism/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/autism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Autism</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Autism</title>
      <link>/tags/autism/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
      <link>/project/asd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/asd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Autism is characterized by social difficulties (e.g., perceiving, interpreting and responding to the intentions and behaviors of others) and non-social difficulties (e.g., sensory and motor atypicalities). Understanding the relationship between social and non-social difficulties in ASD is a major challenge for researchers: do they equally contribute to the condition or one is primary? Are these relationship maintained throughout the spectrum? Do they share the same pathogenesis or different causes drive them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studying the sense of smell in individuals with autism represents a promising tool to answer these questions. Indeed, smelling is a byproduct of involuntary breathing which often occurs outside of conscious awareness, making it a tool usable across the spectrum; body odors continuously transfer a wealth of social information among individuals (see&lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:4321/project/body-odors/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Body Odors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for more details); odor-driven actions can positively impact social behavior (see&lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:4321/publication/journal-article/8_parma-et-al.-2013/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;my work on automatic imitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, investigating the development and the multisensory features of body ownership in ASD (see&lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:4321/publication/journal-article/24_guerra-et-al.-2017/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;my work on the numbness illusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; allows to determine how atypical self-other interactions are initiated and navigated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research in this area investigates the neurobiological basis of social cognition and sensory perception in individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder using behavioral, psychophysiological and neurophysiological techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
